And we will conclude our expedition into the world of frontier models through their chat interface by
그리고 대화 인터페이스를 통해 개척 모델의 세계를 탐구하는 여정을 마무리할 겁니다
looking at meta AI and perplexity.
메타 인공지능과 당혹스러움을 살펴보죠
Meta AI is, of course, the front end version to llama that's running behind the scenes.
메타 인공지능은 라마의 프런트 엔드 버전으로 뒤에서 실행되고 있어요
We can ask it the same question about how does it compare itself to other models, and we'll get back
같은 질문을 할 수도 있어요. 다른 모델과 비교해 보면 장단점이
something that has some strengths and weaknesses.
있는 Get을 얻을 수 있어요.
It doesn't do a great job.
잘 안 되네요
It gives some rather old fashioned complimentary llms, but it's it's okay.
전통적인 무료 llm을 주지만 괜찮아요
And generally speaking, I think you'd find asking various questions that you'll get answers that are
일반적으로 다양한 질문을 하면 괜찮긴 하지만 다른 질문만큼
okay, but not the same power as some of the others.
강력하진 않은 답을 얻게 될 거예요. Get it.
Let's ask the same question.
같은 질문을 해 보죠
You guys are going to be fed up with me for doing this, but how many times does the letter A appear
제가 이런 말을 해서 질리실 텐데 A가 이 문장에 몇 번이나
in this sentence?
나오는 거죠?
And let's see what we get from meta AI.
메타 인공지능은 어떤지 보죠.
It appears five times, so meta is also not able to handle that particular question.
다섯 번 나타나죠 메타도 그 특정 질문을 처리할 수 없어요
Now, one thing that the meta is able to handle is image generation.
메타가 다룰 수 있는 한 가지는 이미지 생성이에요
And we can say please generate an image of a rainbow of rainbows
하와이에서 17로 가는 무지개의 이미지를 생성해
leaping from Hawaii to 17.
달라고 요청할 수 있어요
Uh, and you'll find that this is the kind of, of challenge that, uh, lama is up for.
보시면 아시겠지만 라마에겐 이런 도전이 딱이에요
And it very nicely does it with these four possibilities.
이 네 가지로 아주 잘 표현했어요
And you get this, uh, this kind of effect.
Get it 하면 이런 효과가 나요
And it seems to have, uh, well, Hawaii has appeared, uh, but but some of these are very respectable,
하와이가 등장한 것 같지만 몇몇은 아주 훌륭한 것들이죠
particularly for the open source model that is, uh, Lama sitting behind the scenes.
특히 오픈 소스 모델에게요 무대 뒤에 있는 라마요
All right, let's flip over to perplexity, which is, of course, a search engine, not an LLM.
그럼 이제 검색 엔진으로 넘어가죠 LLM이 아니라요
So it doesn't.
그렇죠
It's the odd one out in this group, although actually, uh, OpenAI also is now in the search space,
이 그룹에서 특이한 경우지만 오픈라이도 검색 영역에 들어왔어요
Um, so really it's looking for, uh, factual questions that it can then research and provide an answer
그래서 사실적인 질문을 찾아서 조사하고 답을 제공하죠
for.
11월 6일에 녹화하고 있습니다 미국 선거 다음 날이죠
So I can say something like, who is the president elect of the United States, and it will do some
미국 대통령 당선자를 이렇게 말하면 생각이 바뀔 거예요
And I would not be surprised at all to see that it's able to summarize back the outcome and give key
결과물을 요약해서 핵심 포인트나 반응 같은 걸 내놓는다 해도
points, reactions and the like.
전혀 놀랍지 않을 거예요
Uh, and so it's able to do this and provide a nuanced, well crafted response to current events.
이 기능을 통해 현안에 대한 미묘하고 정교한 대응을 제공하죠
Actually, if you ask a question like that to, uh, OpenAI to GPT right now, it will also give you
오픈AI에 그런 질문을 해도 좋은 답변을 얻을 수 있습니다 현재 상황을
a good answer, uh, based on current events, despite its knowledge cutoff being last year.
고려하면요 작년 기준으로 제한이 있었지만요
But if you ask Claude, it won't be able to do that.
클로드한테 물어보면 못 할 거예요
And it will say it will say to to be direct.
단도직입적으로 말하라고 할 거예요
My knowledge cutoff is, uh, you get that very specific answer.
아주 구체적인 답을 얻게 되는 게 제 지식의 한계예요 get it get it
Uh, let's ask the question, uh, how many?
질문을 해 보죠 몇 명이죠?
Let's start a new, fresh chat and say, how many times does the letter A appear in this sentence?
새로운 대화를 시작해 보죠 A라는 글자가 이 문장에 몇 번 나오죠?
It's the last time you have to see this.
이걸 보는 건 마지막이에요
Uh, and it says four times.
네 번이라고 쓰여 있어요
So it is able to count.
숫자를 셀 수 있군요
Uh, so it's impressive.
정말 인상적이에요
Uh, don't know whether it's a coincidence, whether it's because other people have written articles
우연의 일치인지 다른 사람들이 기사를 써서
about this that it's found, but it is able to count for times.
발견된 건지는 모르겠지만 숫자를 셀 수 있어요
So perplexity is with the oh one preview version and being able to get this right.
그래서 get One Preview 버전에서 이걸 제대로 하는 게 당혹스러워요
Congratulations to perplexity.
축하해요, 당혹스러움
Um, and now ask a slightly curious question, which is, ah, uh, question about comparing to other
이제 좀 이상한 질문을 해 보죠 다른 모델과 비교해
models, and you'll see a, um, here's the response.
보면 이런 답이 나올 거예요
Uh, the area is indicated by perplexity.
그 지역은 당혹스러움으로 표시돼요
I don't have the capabilities.
전 그럴 능력이 없어요
So it definitely pushes back firmly on that.
확실히 더 강하게 밀어주죠
And that is a wrap on our exploration of frontier models.
이것으로 개척자 모델 탐사를 마칠게요
But now I encourage you to do the same.
하지만 이젠 당신도 그렇게 해요
Come up with interesting questions, particularly try and find questions which are able to bring to
흥미로운 질문을 던지고 특히 모델과 캐릭터의 차이점
the surface the differences between the models, their characters, what they're good at, where they're
장점과 약점을 드러낼 수 있는 질문을 찾으려고 노력해요
And if you find something good, then please share it with me or post it in messages.
그리고 좋은 거 발견하시면 공유나 post 해 주세요
Uh, this is it's really great to find the kinds of prompts that help to surface these differences,
이런 차이를 표면화하고 어디가 가장 큰지 강조할 수 있는 표시를
and also that help to highlight where they are so strong.
찾는 건 정말 좋은 일이에요
And I will see you in the next video to wrap this up.
그럼 다음 비디오에서 마무리하도록 하죠